

# **Hatem Lamine**

Full-stack software engineer

#### Application context:

I am a full-stack software engineer with over 3 years of experience, based in Tunis, Tunisia. Currently, I'm a 5th-year software engineering student at INSAT, and I'm planning a mandatory 6-month end-of-study internship starting anytime after I'll have completed my studies on 13/01/2024. (PS: This is how I managed studying while working full-time in the past.)

My portfolio	
--------------	--

My web-apps

hatemlaminee@gmail.com

+216 93 684 137

linkedin.com/in/hatem-lamine in

github.com/Hatem902

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Full-stack Software Engineer 12/2021 - 11/2023 (2 yrs) <u>XQuant</u> - Seoul, South Korea · Full-time · Remote

- Proposed and implemented an infinite scrolling solution resulting in an exceptional user experience and a 10x performance increase. (Through transforming an initial 6 seconds loading time into virtually unnoticeable 50ms loading times as the user scrolls down.)
- Participated in PR reviews to maintain quality standards.
  - Made decisions paired with constructive comments and feedback, to approve or reject merges involving multiple features, fixes, and refactors.
- Wrote end-to-end high-quality code for complex features.
  - Such as comparing two documents side by side (like github commits), managing user workspaces, and exposing analytical statistics for contract documents.

Tech: Next.js  $\cdot$  React  $\cdot$  Node.js  $\cdot$  TypeScript  $\cdot$  Tailwind  $\cdot$  Radix UI  $\cdot$  React Query + Axios  $\cdot$  React Hook Forms  $\cdot$  Zod  $\cdot$  Docker

# **Full-stack Software Engineer** 11/2020 - 10/2021 (1 yr) <u>EY</u> - Tunis, Tunisia · Full-time · On-site

- Set-up advanced API endpoints with optimized DB queries, and schema validation.
  - Created customizable frontend pages and components that consume them while maintaining end-to-end type safety, graceful error handling, and efficient caching. (In collaboration with the UX/UI design team.)
  - Designed optimal data structures for complex features.
- Set up End-to-End Tests using Cypress with a Test-Driven Development (TDD) approach.
- Contributed to the architectural decisions for two modules within GTES (EY's Global Tax E-invoicing Solution), ensuring a precise alignment with the business requirements.

Tech: Next.js · React · Node.js · TS · Tailwind · React Query · React Hook Forms · Zod · Figma · Docker · Cypress

# Full-stack Web Developer 04/2020 - 09/2020 (6 mos)

Keyrus - Tunis, Tunisia · Internship · On-site

• Migrated a large expense management solution from Nuxt.js 2 to Nuxt.js 3 and created end-to-end features.

Tech: Vue 3 · Nuxt 3 · TS · Node.js · Express.js

# Front-end Web Developer 01/2020 - 02/2020 (2 mos)

UpKurs - Tunis, Tunisia · Internship · On-site

 Implemented 20% of the front-end material for a videoconferencing app, in collaboration with the UX/UI team.

Tech: Angular · TS · CSS · Node.js · Nest.js · Figma

## **TECH STACK**

- Full-stack: Next.js, React, Node.js, TS, React Query, Axios, Zustand/Jotai, Tailwind CSS, Radix UI, Shadcn UI, React Portals, MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, PlanetScale, UpStash, Drizzle ORM, Prisma, NextAuth, Clerk, Stripe, React Hook Forms, Zod, Figma, Express.js, tRPC, Cypress, Playwright.
- DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, AWS, Azure, Vercel.
- Basics: TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Git.
- Concepts: Performance Optimization, Queries & Caching, Error Handling, Testing, TDD, Software Architecture, UX/UI Design, SEO.

## **EDUCATION**

INSAT University - Tunis · 2019 - Present (5th year). Software engineering

Expected software engineering degree in 2024.

Pioneer High School Of Nabeul · 2015 – 2019

Baccalaureate mathematics

Grade: 17.41/20, honors. Rank: 642

#### **PROJECTS**

# Best in Role (peaked 50k+ users)

Esports Voting Platform & Leaderboard, created for the 2023 League of Legends World Championship event.

Targeted application requirements:

- 1- Performance Immediate reactivity through:
  - optimistic updates, lazy loading, efficient caching, parallel queries. Lighthouse Performance score: 100.
- 2- Intuitive, clean UX/UI design: color shades, whitespace, visual hierarchy, responsiveness, attention allocation.
- 3- SEO: Metadata, favicons, sitemaps, OpenGraph images.
  - advertised it through self-promotion & reaching out to influencers on X (Twitter), Reddit, and Twitch.
  - o Lighthouse SEO score: 100.
- 4- Maintainability: Type safety end-to-end, schema validation, customizable typesafe reusable components.

Tech: Next.js App Router & Route handlers  $\cdot$  React  $\cdot$  Node  $\cdot$  TS React Query  $\cdot$  Tailwind  $\cdot$  ShadcnUI  $\cdot$  MySQL  $\cdot$  PlanetScale  $\cdot$  Zod

## E-Commerce + Dashboard & CMS (Demo / Website / Source)

- Admin Dashboard exposing statistics such as total revenue, sales, and products in stock + a highly customizable CMS.
- Multi-platform image upload, auth, stores with seamless navigation & filtering, and cart management & payment.

Tech: Next.js 13.4 · React · Node · TS · React Query · Tailwind · Shadcn UI · Zod · React Hook Form · Stripe · MySQL · PlanetScale.

# Text Similarity API (Demo / Website / Source)

 Measures text similarity using OpenAI's utilities, and a comprehensive API key system with rate limitation.

Tech: Next.js 13.2 · React · Node · TS · Tailwind · Radix UI · PlanetScale · Prisma · Upstash · NextAuth.

# Spotify 2 (<u>Demo</u> /<u>Showcase</u> /<u>Website</u> /<u>Source</u> /<u>My Design</u>)

• A redesigned Spotify experience via your real Spotify account.

Tech: Next.js · React · Spotify API · NextAuth · OAuth & JWT

## **LANGUAGES**

- English
- French

# Arabic

### **HOBBIES**

• Piano, music theory, design, hiking, journaling, working out.